▍2026 国家银行公开赛（多伦多）决赛
斯瓦泰克 6-2 6-3 莱巴金娜 · 赛后新闻发布会
Uh yeah, I think overall the tournament
总体来说 这一站
was successful.
算是成功的
Of course, uh today was uh pity.
当然 今天挺可惜
I didn't have uh much energy.
我没有太多能量了
Uh tried my best, but it wasn't enough.
尽力了 但还不够
And uh anyway, I tried to take only positive
不管怎样 我尽量只把好的一面
from this tournament to uh
从这一站带走
for the next ones.
留给接下来的比赛
Hi Elena, sorry about the loss today.
埃琳娜 今天输球很遗憾
You kind of touched upon it there.
你刚才提到了一点
Just how much was the effect
想问影响到底有多大
of like the three-set matches
那些三盘大战
and your hours on court
还有你在场上的时间
and just consecutively leading into tonight?
一场接一场 一直到今晚
Yeah, I think it was uh um big uh uh how
我觉得影响很大 呃
to say?
怎么说呢
I mean, I was just very tired
我就是太累了
and uh you could see
你们能看出来
that I wasn't pushing with the legs enough
我的腿蹬不动了
and uh a lot of uh unforced errors,
很多非受迫失误
especially on top of the net.
尤其是网前那些
It was just pure lack of concentration
纯粹是注意力不够
and even on these uh kind of easy balls.
连那些简单球都是
So, yeah, and uh uh of course,
当然
Iga, she's uh a tough opponent
伊加是很难打的对手
and uh she was uh trying
她一直在想办法
to get all the balls back uh of course.
把每一个球都救回来
So, yeah, it was uh difficult for me today.
所以今天对我来说很难
And uh yeah,
嗯
I just hope that I take all the lessons
我希望能把这些教训都记住
and uh somehow next time I'm going
希望下次我能
to do better.
做得更好一些
How did you feel coming
今年温网之后
into Toronto this year after Wimbledon?
来到多伦多时你感觉如何
Did you feel like a big result like
你当时有没有感觉
this was something that was coming
这样一个好成绩就要来了
your way uh the way that your game
看你的状态
and your practice was going?
和训练的情况
I was not uh thinking too much how
我没有想太多
the tournament overall will go.
这一站整体会怎么走
I was just uh uh trying
我只是想
to bring everything we worked
把我们之前练的东西
on for a couple of weeks
那几周的功课
before coming here
全都带到场上
and uh um I think we did a good job.
我觉得我们做得不错
So, slowly, match by match,
一场一场慢慢来
I could see the the results,
我能看到结果
some improvement, and I'm just happy
看到一些进步 我很高兴
the way it all went despite the loss today
尽管今天输了
and uh um yeah,
嗯
I think the important right now
我觉得现在最要紧
is just to forget uh this tournament already
是赶紧把这一站忘掉
and try to to prepare for the next one
去准备下一站
and hopefully uh do the same
希望能打得一样好
and even better.
甚至更好
Hi Elena, great tournament.
埃琳娜 这一站打得很棒
Uh I was just wondering,
我想问一下
you obviously the fatigue was a big factor,
疲劳显然是个很大的因素
but it seemed like a couple
但比赛里有几次
of times during the match you
看起来你
were like stretching out your arm.
在拉伸自己的手臂
I was just wondering if that was anything
想问是不是有什么问题
if anything was bothering you there.
那里是不是不舒服
Well, I I'm not sure
我不太确定
if I can tell you what is not hurting actually.
能不能告诉你 哪儿是不疼的
Uh so, yeah.
就这样吧
I feel kind of destroyed of course now
我现在感觉整个人都散了
and uh especially
尤其是
when the tournament is finished,
比赛一打完
uh you feel kind of everything even more.
什么都感觉得更清楚
And uh um I think that this time I actually
不过我觉得这次
did better with a scheduling
我在赛程安排上做得好一些
because uh I was playing a lot of matches
因为我有不少比赛
in the morning during the day,
排在早上和白天
then uh at night, and I think
然后是晚上 我想
that uh this is also um big uh big difference
这也是很大的区别
and this time compare maybe other
跟别的一些赛事比
tournaments I did a bit better,
这次我做得好一点
but uh it was just uh very pity
但还是很可惜
that uh I didn't have enough
我没有足够的力气
to push this last match even more.
在最后这场再往前推一把
Hi there. What made Iga
你好 今晚是什么让伊加
a tough opponent tonight?
成为这么难缠的对手
Well, um she's uh playing really well uh
她防守打得非常好
in defense and then she can uh take
然后她能抓住
the opportunity during the the rally
回合中的机会
and turn it around and uh as I said,
把局面反过来 我刚才也说了
for me I feel like it was more from my side
我觉得更多是我自己的问题
that I wasn't playing aggressive enough,
我打得不够主动
was not with the energy enough to play
也没有足够的能量
against her.
去跟她打
And we all know she's a fighter
我们都知道她很能拼
and she can run left
她能左右奔跑
and right much longer than me
跑得比我久得多
and we have different style of the game,
我们的打法不一样
so I couldn't show my style at my best.
所以我没能打出最好的状态
I tried really till the end and uh I think Yeah,
我真的拼到了最后
just first set starting
只是第一盘开局
with two double faults losing
两个双误
this game also As I said
就丢掉了那一局 我说过
in the previous press conference,
在上一次发布会上
you can't always be chasing.
你不能总是在追赶
You need sometimes to actually start up
有时候得由你先起势
during the matches and for now
在比赛里 而到目前为止
it's been always for me chasing,
我一直都在追赶
so this time I couldn't turn it around,
所以这次我没能反过来
couldn't bring this extra energy,
拿不出那份额外的能量
but uh definitely I think Iga played
但我觉得伊加确实
her game.
打出了她的球
She uh she was fresh and she played better
她更有体力 也打得更好
in some important moments.
在一些关键分上
The gap in the rankings between you
你和萨巴伦卡之间
and Aryna Sabalenka
排名的差距
is really quite close right now
现在其实已经很近了
and I know you've mentioned
我知道你说过
that you don't think
你平时并不怎么
about it much day-to-day,
去想这件事
but when you were a kid,
但你小时候
when you were growing up, did you dream
长大的过程中 有没有梦想过
of being the number one player
成为世界第一
in the world and what would that mean
如果真做到了 那对你
to you if you are able to get there?
意味着什么
Uh well, it would mean definitely a lot
那当然意义重大
and uh I know for me,
对我来说
even if you say by the ranking it's close,
就算你说排名上已经很近
for me it still feels very far
对我来说还是很远
since I'm not thinking about it
因为我并没有
so much and we all still compete,
太去想它 我们都还在比赛
so it doesn't depend only
所以这不只取决于
on me also uh how others are going
我一个人 还要看别人
to do, but uh when I was young,
打得怎么样 而我小时候
I was not even if we talk about kid,
如果说小孩子那会儿
I was not even thinking that I'm going
我甚至没想过
to be professional playing at this level.
自己能打到职业的这个级别
So, I think I achieved quite a lot.
所以我觉得我已经拿到很多了
I'm super happy and if I can do better,
我非常开心 如果能做得更好
amazing.
那就太好了
I try my best
我会尽我所能
and hopefully it it it happens one day.
希望有一天能实现
Thank you.
谢谢